<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Elevate Your Business</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 10:52:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../wp-content/uploads/2024/08/cropped-images-removebg-preview-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Elevate Your Business</title>
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Discover Our Creative Process</title>
		<link>./../discover-our-creative-process/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../discover-our-creative-process/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 10:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With a growing IT sector, Bangladesh has a wide variety of training facilities that deliver students with]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>IT skills are necessary for particular and professional growth in today’s swiftly-changing digital world. The demand for IT professionals in Bangladesh has risen in every sector. People from different backgrounds are now more interested in investing in developing IT expertise. The response to this rising demand, many IT training institutes have come up.</p>



<p>With a growing IT sector, Bangladesh has a wide variety of training facilities that deliver students with the expertise they need to succeed in whatever they pick out. Thousands of institutions out there produce a platform for people to gain knowledge and grow successful in their career path. It’s quite normal to feel lost while choosing the leading freelancing skill development platform for yourself.</p>



<p>Hence, now we will explore the ten best IT training institutes in Bangladesh that have garnered strong fame and are massively regarded by industry professionals. Whether you’re a student, a working professional, or an aspiring entrepreneur, these institutes will help you release new opportunities and thrive in the digital age.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1. Technology knowledge</h2>



<p>Technology is one of the best IT institutes in Bangladesh and is also known as the best training institute. Experienced IT professionals are always ready to give perfect solutions to your IT problems. They are committed to giving you reliable &amp; trusted services for your business.<br>Updated and quality course outlines, hands-on training by experienced IT professionals, and the right directions can make a perfect career path for a new student, and  is dedicated to giving this support.</p>



<p><strong>Courses They Offer:</strong> we provides the most trendy and timely courses; basic to advanced levels to meet the demand of the global market.</p>



<ul>
<li>Web Design &amp; Development</li>



<li>Professional Graphics Design</li>



<li>Digital Marketing</li>



<li>UI/XI Design</li>



<li>Online Marketplace</li>



<li>Business Development</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2. Creative IT Institute</h2>



<p>Creative IT Institute is one of the well-known IT training institutes in Bangladesh. Its reputation for excellence and commitment to providing practical learning makes this institute a great choice to meet the ever-evolving demands of the IT sector. Updated and quality course modules, hands-on training approaches with experienced instructors, regular practice, teamwork, weak student support, 24/7 support, prerequisite support, lab support, and career placement opportunities after course completion make it stand out from other institutes.</p>



<p>A career advancement program has been introduced a career advancement program where students will be closely supervised by mentors. These benefits and training can help you thrive in the digital world.</p>



<p><strong>Courses They Offer:</strong>&nbsp;CIT offers the most trendy courses; basic to advanced levels that have immense demand in the global market.</p>



<p>•Web Development<br>•Professional Graphic Design<br>•Digital Marketing<br>•Mern Stack Development<br>•Motion Graphics<br>•Front Development with React<br>•UI/UX Design<br>•Professional 3D Animation<br>•Content Writing<br>•Ethical Hacking<br>•Cisco CCNA &amp; MTCNA<br>•Mikrotik Networking<br>•Professional Video Editing<br>•Blockchain Technology</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../discover-our-creative-process/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creative Website Buildup</title>
		<link>./../top-5-it-institute-of-bangladesh/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../top-5-it-institute-of-bangladesh/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 10:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[IT skills are necessary for particular and professional growth in today’s swiftly-changing digital world. The demand for IT professionals]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>IT skills are necessary for particular and professional growth in today’s swiftly-changing digital world. The demand for IT professionals in Bangladesh has risen in every sector. People from different backgrounds are now more interested in investing in developing IT expertise. The response to this rising demand, many IT training institutes have come up.</p>



<p>With a growing IT sector, Bangladesh has a wide variety of training facilities that deliver students with the expertise they need to succeed in whatever they pick out. Thousands of institutions out there produce a platform for people to gain knowledge and grow successful in their career path. It’s quite normal to feel lost while choosing the leading freelancing skill development platform for yourself.</p>



<p>Hence, now we will explore the ten best IT training institutes in Bangladesh that have garnered strong fame and are massively regarded by industry professionals. Whether you’re a student, a working professional, or an aspiring entrepreneur, these institutes will help you release new opportunities and thrive in the digital age.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1.Technology knowledge</h2>



<p>Technology is one of the best IT institutes in Bangladesh and is also known as the best training institute. Experienced IT professionals are always ready to give perfect solutions to your IT problems. They are committed to giving you reliable &amp; trusted services for your business.<br>Updated and quality course outlines, hands-on training by experienced IT professionals, and the right directions can make a perfect career path for a new student, and MakrumIT is dedicated to giving this support.</p>



<p><strong>Courses They Offer:</strong>&nbsp;MakrumIT provides the most trendy and timely courses; basic to advanced levels to meet the demand of the global market.</p>



<ul>
<li>Web Design &amp; Development</li>



<li>Professional Graphics Design</li>



<li>Digital Marketing</li>



<li>UI/XI Design</li>



<li>Online Marketplace</li>



<li>Business Development</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2. Creative IT Institute</h2>



<p>Creative IT Institute is one of the well-known IT training institutes in Bangladesh. Its reputation for excellence and commitment to providing practical learning makes this institute a great choice to meet the ever-evolving demands of the IT sector. Updated and quality course modules, hands-on training approaches with experienced instructors, regular practice, teamwork, weak student support, 24/7 support, prerequisite support, lab support, and career placement opportunities after course completion make it stand out from other institutes.</p>



<p>A career advancement program has been introduced a career advancement program where students will be closely supervised by mentors. These benefits and training can help you thrive in the digital world.</p>



<p><strong>Courses They Offer:</strong>&nbsp;CIT offers the most trendy courses; basic to advanced levels that have immense demand in the global market.</p>



<p>•Web Development<br>•Professional Graphic Design<br>•Digital Marketing<br>•Mern Stack Development<br>•Motion Graphics<br>•Front Development with React<br>•UI/UX Design<br>•Professional 3D Animation<br>•Content Writing<br>•Ethical Hacking<br>•Cisco CCNA &amp; MTCNA<br>•Mikrotik Networking<br>•Professional Video Editing<br>•Blockchain Technology</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../top-5-it-institute-of-bangladesh/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Web Design?</title>
		<link>./../what-is-web-design/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../what-is-web-design/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 09:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=1024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Designing a website is abbreviated as web design. Generally what a website will look like depends on the web design. If we analyze a ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Designing a website is abbreviated as web design. Generally what a website will look like depends on the web design. If we analyze a little more, it can be said that what will the logo of a website look like, where will the logo sit, the sidebar of the website will be on the right or left, what will the menu bar look like, what will the color of the website be, what will be the font size of the website posts, where on the website are the advertisements. Space will be kept for etc etc work is done through web design. Basically how we see a website from the outside, is defined or designed through web design.</p>



<p><strong>Type of website</strong><br>There are generally two types of websites for work convenience. For example-</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Static website.</li>



<li>Dynamic website.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Static website<br></strong>A static website does not have any kind of admin panel. That is, to do any work, you have to work directly through coding. Even when writing a post, it has to be placed in the HTML code. Currently, such websites are not in use.</p>



<p><strong>Dynamic website</strong><br>A dynamic website has an admin panel to work with. Basically a dynamic website is created through web development. Such websites require no coding to function normally.</p>



<p>Take this post of mine as an example. I didn’t have to do any HTML or CSS or any other coding to write this post. I created a new post by logging into google blogger with gmail id and posted my post without any coding in post editor. But the work of coding has been completed automatically in the fear of the post. This type of website is called a dynamic website. Here Google Blogger web development has created a dynamic website. And we can use it to share any type of post directly without any coding knowledge. A dynamic website is a website designed without coding and managing related content including content management or content writing through an admin panel.</p>



<p><strong>What is web development?</strong><br>Web development is the task of functionalizing the admin panel of a website to create external parts of a website or to manage content through the admin panel of a website. That is, the code that is coded to do all the functional work of a website is called web development. I am making this more clear through an example.</p>



<p>After logging in to Google Blogger, your blog settings and posts, along with other options, are all done by web development. Moreover, those of you who are using the Magone theme, if you look closely, you will see that SneeitSpot allows you to change the design of the blog. The only options we see to make these changes are through web development.</p>



<p><strong>Type of web developer</strong><br>Web developers can generally be divided into three categories based on the type of work. For example-</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Front End Web Developer</li>



<li>Back end web developer</li>



<li>Fullstack Web Developer</li>
</ul>



<p>Normally a back end developer takes the design codes of a website from the front end developer and creates an admin panel for it. After creating the admin panel, no coding is required to change the design of the website or to write new posts. That is, a backend developer converts a website into a static website.</p>



<p><strong>Fullstack Web Developer</strong><br>A developer who can work on front end development and back end development simultaneously, is called a full stack web developer. Such web developers are very experienced in web development and web design work. Moreover, such web developers are in high demand in both online and offline markets.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../what-is-web-design/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
